# ANTHONY EKWENSI

Melbourne, Australia | +61 406 767 729 | anthonyekwensi@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/anthony-ekwensi

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced Software Developer with a strong background in web development and cybersecurity. Proficient in Git, CI/CD, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Apex, and LWC. Notable achievements include enhancing user engagement by 25% through the development of appealing custom web pages.

### **SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS**

Skills: Git | HTML | CSS | |CI/CD | Good Communication Skills | Programming Skills (JavaScript, React, Apex, LWC).

Certifications: CompTIA Security+

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## BIRDLIFE AUSTRALIA | FULLTIME

Nov 2023 - Present

#### **ICT DEVELOPER**

- Utilized Salesforce proprietary programming languages Apex & LWC to build custom web pages for it's frontend UI, enhancing the user interface and increasing user engagement by 25%.
- Facilitated the diagnosis and troubleshooting of software issues, identifying root causes and providing solutions, reducing incident resolution time by 30%.
- Assisted with the integration of Salesforce and WordPress, ensuring seamless data exchange between the two platforms, which improved data accuracy by 20%.
- Utilized Docker to run an instance of WordPress on my local machine to test code changes before committing them to our GitHub repository which triggered a GitHub action to ensure the code was ultimately merged with production.

## PETPACK AUSTRALIA | FULLTIME

May 2023 – Nov 2023

### **WEB DEVELOPER**

- Worked with a digital marketing agency with over 300 clients, specializing in building software solutions for veterinary clinics.
- Implemented SEO strategies which enhanced organic traffic and keyword rankings for our clients by 15%.
- Helped clients troubleshoot problems and communicated complex solutions in simple terms to nontechnical clients.

### **EDUCATION**

NNAMDI AZIKIWE UNIVERSITY Bachelor of Education (B.Ed)

2015 - 2019

# **References:**

Available on request.